<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on 大香蕉</title>
    <link>https://zkyue.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on 大香蕉</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zh-cn</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 14:26:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://zkyue.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>PatchMatch Stereo</title>
      <link>https://zkyue.github.io/posts/chinese-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 14:26:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zkyue.github.io/posts/chinese-preview/</guid>
      <description>这篇论文是我进入立体匹配领域后读的第一篇论文，读的十分痛苦，最后总算把问题解决了，写篇博客谈谈我的理解。 PatchMatch Stereo 的主要创新点在于： 为了解决 fronto-parallel bias， 引入了 slanted support window 为了寻找 slanted support window， 使用了 PatchMatch 算法 什么</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>日本語敬語体系</title>
      <link>https://zkyue.github.io/posts/japanese-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 14:26:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zkyue.github.io/posts/japanese-preview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;日本語の敬語体系は、一般に、大きく尊敬語・謙譲語・丁寧語に分類される。文化審議会国語分科会は、2007年2月に「敬語の指針」を答申し、これに丁重語および美化語を含めた5分類を示している。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;尊敬語&#34;&gt;尊敬語&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;尊敬語は、動作の主体を高めることで、主体への敬意を表す言い方である。動詞に「お（ご）～になる」を付けた形、また、助動詞「（ら）れる」を付けた形などが用いられる。たとえば、動詞「取る」の尊敬形として、「（先生が）お取りになる」「（先生が）取られる」などが用いられる。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a New Theme</title>
      <link>https://zkyue.github.io/posts/english-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 14:26:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zkyue.github.io/posts/english-preview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tutorial will show you how to create a simple theme in Hugo. I assume that you are familiar with HTML, the bash command line, and that you are comfortable using Markdown to format content. I&#39;ll explain how Hugo uses templates and how you can organize your templates to create a theme. I won&#39;t cover using CSS to style your theme.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theme Preview</title>
      <link>https://zkyue.github.io/posts/theme-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 17:49:40 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zkyue.github.io/posts/theme-preview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;headings&#34;&gt;Headings&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;# H1
## H2
### H3
#### H4
##### H5
###### H6
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://zkyue.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zkyue.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Written in Go, Hugo is an open source static site generator available under the Apache Licence 2.0. Hugo supports TOML, YAML and JSON data file types, Markdown and HTML content files and uses shortcodes to add rich content. Other notable features are taxonomies, multilingual mode, image processing, custom output formats, HTML/CSS/JS minification and support for Sass SCSS workflows.
Hugo makes use of a variety of open source projects including:
 https://github.com/russross/blackfriday https://github.com/alecthomas/chroma https://github.com/muesli/smartcrop https://github.com/spf13/cobra https://github.com/spf13/viper  Hugo is ideal for blogs, corporate websites, creative portfolios, online magazines, single page applications or even a website with thousands of pages.
Hugo is for people who want to hand code their own website without worrying about setting up complicated runtimes, dependencies and databases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cayman Typography</title>
      <link>https://zkyue.github.io/post/cayman-typography/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zkyue.github.io/post/cayman-typography/</guid>
      <description>Text Text can be **bold**, _italic_, or ~~strikethrough~~. [Links](https://github.com) should be blue with no underlines (unless hovered over).  Text can be bold, italic, or strikethrough. Links should be blue with no underlines (unless hovered over).
Paragraph There should be whitespace between paragraphs. There should be whitespace between paragraphs. There should be whitespace between paragraphs. There should be whitespace between paragraphs. There should be whitespace between paragraphs. There should be whitespace between paragraphs. There should be whitespace between paragraphs. There should be whitespace between paragraphs.  There should be whitespace between paragraphs. There should be whitespace between paragraphs. There should be whitespace between paragraphs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Katex Math Typesetting</title>
      <link>https://zkyue.github.io/post/katex-math-typesetting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zkyue.github.io/post/katex-math-typesetting/</guid>
      <description>Enable Katex in the config file by setting the katex param to true. This will import the necessary Katex CSS/JS.
Note: Use the online reference of supported TeX functions.
Some math:
$$ \varphi = \dfrac{1+\sqrt5}{2}= 1.6180339887… $$  $$ \varphi = \dfrac{1+\sqrt5}{2}= 1.6180339887… $$
More math:
$$ \varphi = 1+\frac{1} {1+\frac{1} {1+\frac{1} {1+\cdots} } } $$  $$ \varphi = 1+\frac{1} {1+\frac{1} {1+\frac{1} {1+\cdots} } } $$</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NASA Images</title>
      <link>https://zkyue.github.io/post/nasa-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zkyue.github.io/post/nasa-images/</guid>
      <description>The below images are from the NASA Image and Video Library -- indulge yourself, revel in their beauty. Also, the built-in figure shortcode is shown for each image.
{{&amp;lt; figure img=&amp;quot;sun.jpg&amp;quot; caption=&amp;quot;The Sun is the star at the center of the Solar System. It is a nearly perfect sphere of hot plasma, with internal convective motion that generates a magnetic field via a dynamo process. It is by far the most important source of energy for life on Earth. [Credits](https://images.nasa.gov/details-GSFC_20171208_Archive_e000393.html).&amp;quot; command=&amp;quot;Resize&amp;quot; options=&amp;quot;800x&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}    The Sun is the star at the center of the Solar System. It is a nearly perfect sphere of hot plasma, with internal convective motion that generates a magnetic field via a dynamo process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(Hu)go Template Primer</title>
      <link>https://zkyue.github.io/post/hugo-template-primer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zkyue.github.io/post/hugo-template-primer/</guid>
      <description>Hugo uses the excellent Go html/template library for its template engine. It is an extremely lightweight engine that provides a very small amount of logic. In our experience that it is just the right amount of logic to be able to create a good static website. If you have used other template systems from different languages or frameworks you will find a lot of similarities in Go templates.
This document is a brief primer on using Go templates. The Go docs provide more details.
Introduction to Go Templates Go templates provide an extremely simple template language. It adheres to the belief that only the most basic of logic belongs in the template or view layer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrate to Hugo from Jekyll</title>
      <link>https://zkyue.github.io/post/migrate-from-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zkyue.github.io/post/migrate-from-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>Move static content to static Jekyll has a rule that any directory not starting with _ will be copied as-is to the _site output. Hugo keeps all static content under static. You should therefore move it all there. With Jekyll, something that looked like
▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/ ▾ images/ logo.png  should become
▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/ ▾ static/ ▾ images/ logo.png  Additionally, you&#39;ll want any files that should reside at the root (such as CNAME) to be moved to static.
Create your Hugo configuration file Hugo can read your configuration as JSON, YAML or TOML. Hugo supports parameters custom configuration too.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>